Hey Joe.
Joe
Wait a second.
等一下
You gave the students the Did you feel it app that just crashes?
你给学生的 Did you feel it 应用 发生崩溃？
&gt;&gt; Yes I did.
— 是的
&gt;&gt; What's up with that?
— 发生什么了？
&gt;&gt; Well, I wanted them to see that the app crashed because
— 我想让学生看到这款 应用因为出现异常
an exception occurred.
而崩溃
&gt;&gt; Okay. &gt;&gt; And the exception that occurred was
— 好吧 — 出现的异常称为
called the NetworkOnMainThreadException.
NetworkOnMainThreadException
&gt;&gt; Wait, but did you explain what that means?
— 等等 你解释了 这是什么意思吗？
&gt;&gt; No, but I have an idea how we can do that.
— 没有 但我想到了 如何解释
&gt;&gt; Okay, let's see it.
— 好的 让我们来听听看
&gt;&gt; Okay. Well, the NetworkOnMainThreadException
— 好吧 NetworkOnMainThreadException
means that we're doing a network operation on the main thread, and
的意思是 我们正在主线程上 执行网络操作 而这是
that is not allowed.
不允许的
&gt;&gt; Wait, but when you say network,
— 但你说到了网络
you mean like a network request like we learned in the last lesson?
意思是像我们上节课中 学到的网络请求一样？
&gt;&gt; Yes. &gt;&gt; Okay, but
— 是的 — 好的 但
you'd also said on the main thread?
你还提到了主线程？
The student's probably wondering what that means too.
学生可能也希望了解 主线程是什么意思
&gt;&gt; Precisely.
— 正好
So I've got some thread to explain it.
我带来了一些线来进行解释
[SOUND] Here, hold this.
给 拿着
&gt;&gt; What the.
— 这是
&gt;&gt; This thread will represent the main thread of the App.
— 这捆线将代表 应用的主线程
A thread is a container that holds a sequence of instructions,
线程是保存指令 序列的容器
such as your Java code, that the device will execute.
例如 设备将执行的 Java 代码
And it's needed by Android to schedule all the tasks that need to be run on
并且 Android 需要它来安排 所有需要在设备硬件上
the device's hardware.
运行的任务
So when building Android apps,
所以在构建 Android 应用时
it's important to understand that the application code is run by default on
理解应用程序代码 默认在主线程上运行
what is called the main thread, which is also known as the UI thread.
是极为重要的 主线程也称为 UI 线程
Let's elaborate on this.
让我们进行详细说明
The main thread handles drawing operations in responses to
主线程可处理绘图操作 以响应用户输入
user input like clicks, scrolling, and that sort of thing.
像点击 滚动之类
Now the main thread can only handle one event at a time, so
但主线程一次只能 处理一个事件 所以
if a bunch of things try to happen around the same time,
如果在同一时间 发生多起事件
they're going to get put into a queue just like this.
这些事件会像这样 被放到队列中
&gt;&gt; Wait, so a queue's like when I go to the grocery store and
— 所以队列就像是 我走进杂货店
I'm in like the longest line ever and
然后我站在很长的队伍中
there's only one checkout person that can process a customer at a time?
但只有一位收银员 每次只能接待一位顾客？
&gt;&gt; Yep.
— 是的
&gt;&gt; Jeez.
— 哇哦
&gt;&gt; That's the type of queue.
— 这就是队列类型
These UI are drawing, and
这些 UI 是绘图操作
user input events are handled one at a time in sequential order.
每次只能按照队列顺序 处理一个用户输入事件
&gt;&gt; So far, all the code we've written has been executing on the main thread.
— 到目前为止 我们编写的所有 代码都已在主线程中执行
When you read Java code, you read from the top to the bottom.
当读取 Java 代码时 可以从上到下读取
Possibly looping or picking a particular branch, or
可以循环或选取 特定分支 或
jumping into and out of other methods.
跳入跳出其他方法
When the program executes,
运行程序时
it has to wait for one task to complete before moving onto the next.
移动到下一个任务前 必须等待前一个任务完成
That's pretty much what a single thread does.
这大致就是单线程 的操作流程
Execute Java in the order it was written.
按编写的顺序 运行 Java
Hold on a second.
等下
So Joe, students may be thinking, if our code has worked fine so far,
所以 Joe 学生可能会想 如果我们 的代码到目前为止都运行良好
why don't we just continue writing all our code on the main thread?
那我们为什么不继续在主线程 中编写我们的所有代码呢？
&gt;&gt; That's a great question.
— 这是个好问题
Let me show you why.
让我来演示下为什么